런던
영국 카팍스
사뮤엘 빌링턴 부자
여기다 상자를 뿌려
Here we go.
Swing it round here.
Master.
주인님!
I am here to do your bidding.
저 여기 있습니다
런던 카팍스 아비
Master! I am here!
주인님! 저 여기 있어요
I have worshipped you.
저는 당신을
숭배합니다
Contrary to some beliefs,
the vampire...
일반의 믿음과는
달리 흡혈귀는
Iike any other night creature,
can move about by day...
정상적인 활동시간이 아니라
비록 세력은 약해지지만
낮에도 이동할 수 있다
though it is not his natural time,
and his powers are weak.
동물원에서 늑대 탈출
기상이변
배 안에서 선원 실종
영화 구경을 오세요
See the amazing cinematograph!
현대 문명의 기적!
A wonder of modern civilization!
The latest sensation!
모두가 놀랄
세기적인 대발명!
The greatest attraction
of the century!
안 보면 후회해요
The new wonder of the world!
영화들 보러 오세요
See me.
나를 보라
See me now.
폭풍이 영국에 상륙했습니다
Escaped wolf from zoo
still at large!
늑대가 탈출했어요
Buy a paper, sir?
1부 드릴까요?
Thank you, sir.
고맙습니다
신문 1부에 1페니!
Get your Gazette!
Penny a paper!
사과 드리겠소
My humblest apologies.
내 실수를
용서하시오
Forgive my ignorance.
I am recently arrived
from abroad...
외국에서 방금와서
지리를 몰라요
and I do not know your city.
- Is a beautiful lady--
- A street atlas is sixpence. Good day.
- 길 안내를 좀...
- 지도를 사세요
화나셨군요
I have offended you.
극장을 찾고 있소
I am only looking for
the cinematograph.
단지 이곳의 문화를
접해보고 싶어서 그래요
I understand it is a wonder
of the civilized world.
If you seek culture,
then visit a museum.
그럼 박물관에 가세요
런던은 박물관으로
가득찬 도시니까요
London is filled with them.
Excuse me.
리시움 극장 햄릿 공연중
당신 같은 미인은
A woman so lovely and intelligent...
should not bewalking the streets
of London without her gentleman.
혼자 다니면 위험해요
Do I know you, sir?
저를 아세요?
제 남편 친구신가요?
Areyou acquainted
with my husband?
Shall I call the police?
경찰을 부르겠어요
Husband?
남편?
I shall bother you no more.
실례 많았소
Sir.
선생님!
It is I who have been rude.
제가 무례했어요
- 극장은...
- 우선
- If you're looking--
- Please.
내 소개부터 하리다
Permit me to introduce myself.
I am Prince Vlad of Sagite.
사카이의
블라드왕자요
- A prince, no less?
- I am...
- 왕자라구요?
- 그렇습니다, 만나서 반갑소
your servant.
Wilhelmina Murray.
미나 머레이예요
뵙게되서
I am...
영광이요
honored...
머레이 부인
Madam Mina.
This way.
이리 오세요
어서 오십시요
Hello, sir.
홈우드의 연락을 받고 왔네
Mr. Holmwood asked me
to stop by to see Miss Lucy.
알겠습니다
Yes, sir.
- Dr. Seward, Miss Lucy.
- Thank you.
소워드 박사 오셨습니다
고맙네
어서 와요, 잭
Oh, Jack!
드레스 어때요?
Brilliant Jack.
Do you like it?
Did Arthur put you up to this...
아더가 오라던가요?
or did you want me alone just once
before I'm married?
내가 보고 싶어서 온 거죠?
루시, 그러지 말아요
Lucy, you're embarrassing me.
I'm here as your doctor.
난 의사로서
찾아온 거요
Your fiance
is very worried aboutyou...
아더가 걱정합니다
and I assure you,
a doctor's confidence is sacred.
의사의 직무는 신성한 거요
날 믿어야 돼요
I must have your complete trust.
도와줘요, 잭
Help me, Jack.
잘은 모르겠지만
내 몸이 이상해요
I don't know
what's happening to me.
I'm changing.
변하고 있어요
I can feel it.
난 느껴요
I can hear everything.
모든 게 들려요
하인들의 속삭임 소리
I hear the servants at the other
end of the house, whispering.
천정에서 쥐가
우는 소리조차도...
I hear mice in the attic,
stomping like elephants.
But I'm having horrible
nightmares, Jack.
하지만, 밤에는 악몽을 꿔요
그 눈!
The eyes.
Oh, Jack.
염려 말아요
I'm here, Lucy.
Nothing will harm you.
내가 지켜주리다
곧 나을 거요
Let it work.
고마워요
- Thank you.
- Lucy.
키스 해줘요
Oh, Jack, kiss me.
루시는 애마부인처럼
And may I say, Miss Lucy
is hotter than a June bride...
뜨거운 여자야
ridin' bareback
buck naked in the Sahara.
이 친구, 말 좀가려서 하게
I would watch my colonial tongue
if I were you.
이봐, 잭
Hello, Jack.
And how's our lovely patient today?
루시는 어떤가?
Well, frankly, Arthur,
I'm confounded.
나도 뭐가 뭔지 모르겠네
아직 루시를 사모하나?
Jack, are you still
broodin' over Miss Lucy?
I can only conclude
it must be something mental.
정신적인 문제같아
말도 안돼
How very droll.
Did you hear that, Quince?
Last week he wanted to marry her,
and now he wants to have her committed.
실연 당했다고
그녀를 정신병자로 모는군
Let's have a look at her.
어디 보세
I'm at a loss, I admit.
원인을 모르겠어
I've taken the liberty
of cabling Abraham Van Helsing...
반 헬싱 교수에게 전보를 쳤네
the metaphysician/philosopher.
Sounds like a goddamn
witch doctor to me,Jack.
그자는 무당이잖아
Van Helsing knows more about obscure
diseases than any man in the world.
이 방면에 최고의 전문가야
He's my teacher and mentor.
내 스승이셨고...
비용은 걱정말고...
Do it, man.
Bring him here.
Spare no expense.
오라고 해
멋지군요
Astounding.
과학에 한계란 없는것 같아요
There are no limits to science.
How can you call this science?
이게 과학인가요?
퀴리부인이 보면 통곡하겠네요
Do you think Madam Curie
would invite such comparisons?
Really.
괜히 왔군요
I shouldn't have come here.
가겠어요
I must go.
두려워 마시오
Do not fear me.
이러지 마세요
Stop this.
왜 이래요!
당신은 누구죠?
My God. Who are you?
I know you.
난 당신을 알아요
I have crossed oceans of time...
난 당신을 만나려고
to find you.
시간의 강을 건너왔소
여러분, 겁내지 마십시오
There is no need to panic.
조련사가 곧 도착 할겁니다
The animal handlers have
everything under complete control.
이리와요, 미나
Come here, Mina.
He likes you.
당신을 좋아하는군요
짐승에겐 배울게 많소
There is much to be learned
from beasts.
알 수 없는 병으로
친구가 죽어감
도움이 필요함, 잭 소워드
열대 흡혈 박쥐는
The tropical pampas vampire bat
must...
consume ten times its own weight
in fresh blood each day...
매일 체중의 10배의
피를 먹어야 살수 있습니다
or its own blood cells will die.
안그러면 자신의
혈구가 죽어버리죠
Cute little vermin, ja?
귀여운 녀석...
Blood and the diseases
of the blood...
오늘의 주제는
such as syphilis,
they concern us here.
혈액의 질병입니다
'비너스의 병'이라는 성병은
The very name
"venereal diseases"...
the diseases of Venus,
imputes to them divine origin.
기독교 문화에서
And they are involved
in that sex problem about which...
금기시 되고 있는
the ethics and ideals
of Christian civilization are concerned.
성문제와 직결되는 병입니다
In fact, civilization and syphilization
have advanced together.
하지만 진실은 문화와
성병은 공존해왔습니다
- 뭔가?
- 전보입니다
- What is this?
- It's from the telegraph, Professor.
Telegraph?
전보?
Thankyou. Gentlemen, thank you.
That will be all.
고맙네
오늘 수업은 이상
Dawn.
새벽이다
이것이 마지막 일기일지 모른다
These may be the last words
I write in thisj ournal.
Dracula has left me
with these women...
드라큐라가 나를 가두어 놓고
이 세 악마로 하여금지키게 했다
these devils of the pit.
나를 약하게 만들기 위해
날마다 나의 피를
They drain my blood
to keep me weak...
빨아먹고 있어 탈출은 커녕
간신히 살아있다
barely alive so I cannot escape.
오늘 마지막으로 탈출을
시도해볼 작정이다
I will try one last time today
to escape to the water.
There must be passageway
to the river...
분명 강으로 통하는
출구가 있을 것이다
악마가 지배하는
and then away
from this cursed land...
이 지옥을 벗어나고 싶다
where the devil and his children
still walk with earthly feet.
For the record, I do attest...
그 전보로 인해
that at this point,
I, Abraham Van Helsing...
나 아브라함 반 헬싱은
그 사건에 개입하게 됐다
became personally involved
in these strange events.
교수님, 와주셨군요
Professor Van Helsing,
how good of you to come.
I always come to my friends in need
when they call me.
사랑스런 제자가
부르는데 와야지
증세를 말해보게
So, Jack, tell me everything
about your case.
빈혈이 심합니다
She has all the usual
physical anemic signs.
Her blood analyzes normal,
and yet it is not.
혈액은 정상인데
She manifests continued blood loss.
I cannot trace the cause.
계속 출혈하고 있어요
- 이유를 모르겠어요
- 출혈?
Blood loss? How?
My God, close the doors!
창문을 닫아
My God...
세상에!
she's only a child.
아직 어리잖아
Ja.
My God.
맙소사
There's no time to lose.
There must be a transfusion at once.
시간이 없네
빨리 수혈해야 돼
Take off your coat.
Remember how to tie a tourniquet?
상의를 벗게
지혈대 묶는법 알지?
- Or have you forgotten?
- You perfected a procedure?
수혈해 보셨어요?
Perfected? No.
I've only experimented.
아니, 실험용 동물한테만 해봤어
Landsteiner's method.
Animals, goats, sheeps.
염소하고 양 같은 동물들...
If hemolysis occurs
in the blood donor serum...
용혈이 생기면
적혈구가 파괴돼서
her red blood cells will explode.
She will die.
Take this tube.
죽을지도 몰라
What in God's name
is going on up here?
뭐하는 거야?
This is Professor Van Helsing, Art.
반 헬싱 교수일세
- 뭐하는 거야?
- 루시를 살리려는 거야
- What the hell is he doing to Lucy?
- He's trying to save her life.
- 맙소사
- 약혼자요? 비켜요!
- Good God!
- You're the fiance? Please.
물러서요
Take off your coat.
This young lady's very ill. She's dying.
상의를 벗어요
이 여자는 죽어가고 있소
이 여자는 수혈을
받아야 하오
She wants blood
and blood she must have.
Take off your coat.
상의를 벗어요
Roll up your sleeve, Art.
팔을 걷게
- 하나님!
- 빨리!
- Oh, God.
- Quickly, quickly.
Roll it up!
어서 걷어요
This may hurt a little, Art.
좀 아플 거야
이 여자는 제 인생의
의미 입니다
Forgive me. My life is hers. I would
give my last drop of blood to save her.
저의 피를 모두 줘도 좋습니다
Your last drop?
모두?
Thank you.
고맙지만 그렇게 많이는
필요 없소
You are very welcome here.
I don't ask as much as that. Not yet.
아직까지는...
Hold her hand.
손을 붙잡아
이틀간 두 명의 피를
수혈 받았어
Jack, that poor creature has had the
blood of two men put into her already.
말도 안돼
빈혈이 그렇게 심한가?
Man alive. Herwhole body
couldn't hold that much blood.
- 원인이 뭘까?
- 좋은 질문이요
- What took it out?
- That's a good question, Mr. Morris.
Those marks on her throat--
목의 상처도
no disease, no trituration--
출혈을 한게 틀림 없어요
흔적이 없잖아요
I am sure the blood loss
occurred there.
Oh? Where did the blood go?
출혈을 했으면
그 피가 어디 갔겠나?
You were once
a careful student, Jack.
한때 자네는
똑똑한 학생이었네
Use your brain!
Where did the blood go?
잘 생각해봐!
피가 어디로 갔겠나?
Tell me!
- The bed would be covered in blood.
- Exactly.
- 이불에 묻었겠죠
- 그래
You do not let your eyes see
noryour ears hear...
헌데 아무런 흔적이 없잖아
that which you cannot account for.
뭔가가 피를
빨아먹었다 이겁니까?
Something just went up there,
sucked it out of her and flew away?
왜 웃나?
Ja. Why not?
That's brilliant.
That's absolutely brilliant.
그런 헛소리 그만하고
Will one of you learned doctors--
orwhateveryou are--
의학을 배웠다는 지식인들이니
과학적인 설명을 해보세요
kindly tell me
what is going on with my Lucy?
Jack, you are a scientist.
잭, 자네는 과학자야
Doyou not think there are things in
this universe you cannot understand...
이 세상에는 과학으로
설명 안되는 일이 있어
and which are true--
mesmerism, hypnotism?
- 최면술
- 하지만 그건...
You and Charcot
have proved hypnotism.
혼령의 현신, 성기체 같은 것...
Materialization, astral bodies.
Professor?
교수님!
Where did he go?
어디 갔지?
You see?
봤지?
I feel like a blundering novice.
장난 그만하세요
Gentlemen, we're not fighting
some disease here.
우리는 지금
병과 싸우자는게 아니오
Those marks on your dear
Miss Lucy's neck were made...
루시의 목의 상처는 불가사의한
존재에 의해 생긴 거야
by something unspeakable
out there.
Dead, but not dead.
죽었고, 하지만 살아있지
It stalks us for some dread purpose
I do not comprehend.
놈은 자기가 살기 위해
To live, it feeds
on Lucy's precious blood.
루시의 소중한 피를
빨아먹고 있는 거야
그놈은 괴물이지
It is a beast, a monster.
도대체 루시와 내게 무슨 일이
일어나고 있는걸까?
What is happening
to Lucyand to me?
When I was younger,
my feelings were never troubled.
마음이 이렇게까지
혼란스러운적이 없었는데...
다시 예전의 내 모습과
I wish I were myself again...
서로를 기댈수 있던
미나의 모습으로 돌아가고 싶다
the sensible Mina
I always depended on.
Absinthe...
쑥 술은
최음 효과가 있소
is the aphrodisiac of the self.
The green fairy...
쑥에 있는
풀의 요정이
who lives in the absinthe...
wants your soul.
사람의 혼을
빼앗거든
하지만
But...
you are safe with me.
내가 지켜주리다
고향 얘기 좀
Tell me, Prince...
tell me of your home.
해주세요
The most beautiful place...
참 아름다운 곳이요
in all creation.
Yes, it must be.
그럴것 같아요
A land beyond
a great, vast forest...
그 곳은 울창한 숲과
surrounded by
majestic mountains...
광활한 산맥에 둘러싸이고
포도넝쿨과
lush vineyards...
and flowers of such frailty
and beauty...
꽃이 우거진
환상적인 곳일 거예요
as to be found nowhere else.
본 것처럼 잘 아는군요
You've described my home...
as if you had seen it firsthand.
It's your voice, perhaps.
당신의 목소리가
귀에 익어요
It's so familiar.
It's like--
꿈속에서 들은 목소리같아요
그 목소리는 내게...
It's like a voice in a dream
I cannot place...
위안을 줘요
and it comforts me.
- When I am alone.
- When you are alone.
- 내가 외로울때...
- 당신이 외로울때...
And what of the princess?
공주님은요?
Princess?
공주?
There is always a princess...
부인 말이예요
with gowns flowing white.
하얀 가운을 입고
그리고 얼굴은...
And her face.
Oh, God...
오, 하나님
her face...
얼굴은...
is a river.
강이예요
The princess...
그녀는...
슬픔으로 가득찬
강물이예요
she's a river
filled with tears of sadness...
and heartbreak.
눈물의 강...
There was a princess.
공주가 있었소
Elisabeta.
엘리자벳
She was the most radiant woman...
세상에서 제일가는 미인이었지
in all the empires of the world.
Man's deceit took her
from her ancient prince.
그녀는 내가 죽은 줄 알고
She leapt to her death...
당신이 말하던 그 강물에
뛰어들어 자살했소
into the river that you spoke of.
In my mother's tongue...
그 강을
it is called...
우리 나라에서
argesh.
이렇게 부르지
River princess.
공주의 강
Dear Madam.
부인
Your fiance is safe andin the care...
아가사수녀의 편지
8월 12일
하커씨는 지금
저희 수도원에 계십니다
of the goodsisters
of the Blessed Sacrament.
그분은 당신이 매우 위험한
상황에 처해있다 생각하여
Mr. Harker believes your life
is in extreme danger...
이곳으로 빨리 오셔서
and he desires with all urgency
that you join him here...
so that you may
immediately be married.
결혼하길 바라십니다
Yours with all blessings,
Sister Agatha.
신의 가호를...
아가사 수녀
왕자님 얘기를
My sweet prince.
Jonathan must never know of us.
그이가 알면 안돼
반 헬싱이요
Dr. Van Helsing.
반 헬싱박사님
루시친구 미나양이죠?
And you're Madam Mina,
dear friend to our Lucy, ja?
- How is she, doctor?
- She's still very weak.
루시는 어때요?
아직도 아파요
She tells me of your
beloved Jonathan Harker...
약혼자가 걱정되겠구려
and your worry for him.
Well, I, too, worry
for all young lovers.
사랑이란 그런 거요
There are darknesses in life,
my child...
세상엔 빛과 어둠이
and there are lights.
공존하죠
You are one of the lights,
dear Mina...
당신은 빛이요
the light of all light.
아주 밝은 빛
Go now.
See your friend.
루시한테 가봐요
오늘 달라보이네
You look different.
You look positively radiant.
표정이 밝아
You heard from Jonathan.
조나단한테서
소식이 온 모양이지?
- Didn't you?
- Yes.
그래!
무사히 잘있대
He's safe.
He's in a convent in Romania.
루마니아의
수도원에 있대
He's suffering
from a violent brain fever.
뇌막염에 걸렸대
The good sisters
are caring for him.
수녀가 편지를 보냈어
날더러 오래
They wrote to me,
and they say he needs me...
but I won't go.
하지만 안갈 거야
I'm not going to leave you.
널 떠날 순 없어
You've got to go to him...
가야 돼
and you've got to love him...
넌 조나단과
결혼을 해야 돼
and marry him
right then and there.
And I want you to take this,
my sister.
이 반지 받아
결혼 선물이야
It's my wedding gift toyou.
Don't worry about
spoiled little Lucy.
내 걱정은 마
난 괜찮아
I'll be all right.
Tell Jonathan oceans of love.
조나단에게 안부 전해줘
Jack, how is she?
어떤가?
숨을 못 쉬겠어!
This is why I cannot breathe!
이건 잠 오게 하는 약이요
Lucy, it's medicinal.
To help you sleep.
To dream better dreams.
마늘일 뿐이예요
It's garlic!
It's nothing but common garlic!
퀸시가 왔소
Quincey's here to see you.
Get some brandy.
브랜디 가져와요
Now, Miss Lucy,
you just rest easy.
루시, 그냥 편히 쉬어요
아더가 가보라고 해서 왔소
Arthur sent me
to take care of you.
빨리 안 나으면 날
죽여버린 답니다
He said
if you don't get better quick...
I have to put you out of your misery
like a lame horse.
You're such a beast.
당신은 짐승이야
키스해줘요
Will you kiss me?
Kiss me.
어서요
키스해 줘요
망할 놈의 영감!
- That old coot!
- Get off me!
저리 비켜요
어서 자요
Listen to me!
Sleep, sleep now. Sleep.
You're at peace.
빨리 자라니까!
이것 봐
Look. There. There.
Nosferatu.
흡혈귀의 짓이야
흡혈귀
" Here occurs the shocking
and frightening history...
이것은 죽음의 왕자
of the wild,
berserk Prince Dracula--
드라큐라에 관한
공포의 기록이다
드라큐라의 잔인함을 말해준다
How he impaled people
and roasted them...
적의 머리를 잘라
솥에 끓이고
boiled their heads in a kettle...
그는 적군의
가죽을 벗기고
how he skinned them alive...
and hacked them to pieces
and then drank their blood."
몸을 조각조각 잘라내고
그 피를 마셨다
Dracul.
드라큐라...
For blood is the life.
피는 생명이라...
"My dearest Prince, forgive me.
왕자님, 용서하세요
루마니아에 있는 약혼자에게
편지를 받고
I have received word
from my fiance in Romania.
I am en route tojoin him.
We are to be married.
약혼자와 결혼하러
루마니아에 갑니다
I will never see you again.
다시는 못만날 거예요
Mina. "
미나 올림
It is odd,
but I feel almost...
왕자님이 곁에 있는 느낌이 든다
that my strange friend
is with me.
He speaks to me in my thoughts.
그분과 있을 땐
기운이 솟는 것 같았는데
With him I felt more alive
than ever I had.
And now without him,
soon to be a bride...
결혼을 앞둔 지금은
마음이 불안하다
I feel confused and lost.
Perhaps, though I try to be good,
I am bad.
나는 나쁜 여자인가보다
Perhaps I am a bad,
inconstant woman.
부도덕한 여자일지도 모르지
Winds!
바람아
불어라
원인은 그거야
It is the cause.
바로 그거라구
It is the cause of my soul!
It is Dracula...
드라큐라
the undead...
안죽었어!
the foe I have pursued
all my life.
내가 평생 추적해온 원수
Dracula!
드라큐라!
Jack, hurry!
I have much to tell you.
잭, 어서 마차에 타
루시를 잘 돌보게
Guard her well, Mr. Morris.
Do not fail here tonight.
여길 떠나면 안돼
상대는 거대한 힘을 갖고 있어
그러니 그녀를 잘 보호하게
We are dealing with forces
beyond all human experience...
an enormous power,
so guard herwell.
잘못하면 루시가 밤의 창녀로
Otherwise your precious Lucy
will become a bitch of the devil...
a whore of darkness!
전락할지 몰라
미친 늙은이!
You're a sick old buzzard.
Hear me out, young man.
내 말 잘 듣게
루시는 선의의 피해자가 아냐
내말 이해가나? 아닐꺼야
Lucy is not a random victim
attacked by mere accident.
Do you understand? No.
She is a willing recruit,
a breathless, wanton follower.
열렬히 놈을 숭배하고 있는
추종자란 말이야
I dare say, a devoted disciple.
악마의 첩이라구
She is the devil's concubine!
Do you understand me?
알겠나?
Yet, we may still save
her precious soul.
아직 기회는 있어
But not on an empty stomach.
하지만, 금강산도 식후경
- Jack!
- Here, sir.
- 잭
- 여기요
밥부터 먹고 보세
I starve. Feed me.
돌았군!
You old coot!
너는 절대 내 손아귀에서
Your impotent men
with their foolish spells...
빠져 나갈 수 없어
cannot protect you
from my power.
넌 영원히 죽지 않고
I condemn you to living death...
to eternal hunger...
인간의 피를 찾아
for living blood.
헤메이게 될 것이다
I know how deeply you loved her. That
is whyyou must trust me and believe.
루시를 사랑했지?
그럼 날 믿게
뭘 말입니까?
Believe?
How can I believe?
I want you to bring me, before
nightfall, a set of postmortem knives.
오늘밤 전에
검시용 칼을 구해오게
An autopsy? Lucy?
루시를 해부하게요?
아니 목을 자르고
심장을 꺼내려고 그래
No, not exactly. I just want to cut off
her head and take out her heart.
9월 17일의 일기
Diary, 17.th September.
조나단은 아직도 아프지만
Poor Jonathan.
He's still so ill.
런던에 와서
기운을 많이 차렸다
He's cheered by
the familiar streets in London.
그러나 난 루시가 죽어 슬프다
For me, now that Lucy is dead,
it is a sad homecoming.
It is as if apart of me
is dead too...
지금 내게 남은 건
왕자님을 만나리라는
except for the tiny hope
that lives in me...
that I will again
see my prince.
한 가닥 희망뿐...
Is he here?
어디 계실까?
Now that I am married...
결혼한 지금에야
내가 그분을 사랑하고 있었음을
I begin to understand the nature
of my feelings for my strange friend...
이제야 깨달았다
who is always in my thoughts.
조나단, 왜 그래요?
Jonathan, what is it?
It is the man himself.
바로 그자야
젊어졌군!
Look, he's grown young.